# AMRITENDU BHATTACHARJEE

Senior Software Engineer

# **ABOUT ME**

Hi, I am a Senior Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience, and I am passionate about creating solutions that can make a positive impact in the real world. A usual day in my schedule involves developing business requirements into live features, taking part in architectural discussions for feature development, peer reviewing and sometimes hosting sessions on various topics for juniors and interns. I am originally from Kolkata and currently residing in Bengaluru. At home one will mostly find me spending time with my dog or working on personal projects. Other than that, I love to read on various topics ranging from human evolution to science fiction. I believe that art is as much important in a person's life as any other field because it helps build the soul while commerce and science build the mind.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Southampton**

MS in Cybersecurity 2015 – 2016

### **West Bengal University of Technology**

Bachelor of Computer Application 2011 – 2014

# CERTIFICATIONS & RECOGNITION

- Hacker Rank React
- Hacker Rank Javascript
- Best Team of the Quarter Dec 2019
- Star Performer Dec 2019
- · Won Hackathon for Client

#### SKILLS & TECHNOLOGY

Frontend: React | ReactNative | MobX |
Redux | Typescript | MUI | ReactQuery |
Tailwind | Webpack | NextJS | Gatsby |
Storybook | ShadCn | Bryntum | HTML | CSS |
JavaScript | Bootstrap | AmCharts |
GoogleMap | Mapbox

**Backend:** NodeJS | ExpressJS | NestJS | Encryption | GraphQL | Redis | WebSockets | RabbitMQ

**Database:** Postgres | MongoDB |
DynamoDB | DocumentDB | AuroraDB

**DevOps:** EC2 | Amplify Hosting | Docker | Jenkins | Azure Pipeline | Github Actions & Workflow

Project management Tools: GitHub |
GitLab | JIRA | ClickUp | Azure Boards |
Trello | Confluence | AGILE

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Senior Software Engineer at Optym

April 2022 - Present

- Worked on the application layer of optimizer for Southwest Airlines.
- Created react components library to be used across projects.
- Successfully delivered POCs to gain new clients.
- Implemented AES encryption system for web application
- Spearheaded development of SaaS and B2B applications related to Logistics Optimization and Supply Chain Management and implemented customized Gantt Scheduler
- Successfully optimized workflows to enhance performance
- Mentored juniors on React and development patterns
- Established secure coding practices
- Worked on live maps, graphs and tracking features

#### Software Engineer at Razrlab

May 2020 - April 2022

- Mostly worked on the MERN stack application
- Created a PaaS product that served 15 B2B clients from a single generator stack
- Implemented custom RSA for secure sharing
- Worked on tracking systems for the Dubai Police
- Implemented end-to-end encryption system for secure communication using WebSockets
- Implementing broker agents like RabbitMQ.
- · Node server with caching and microservices

# Fullstack Developer | SME at Nat IT Solved, presently CBNITS

November 2018 - April 2020

- Implemented UI workflow for interactive learning application on ReactNative
- Created outlook add-in for seamless integration of security features
- Implemented file encryption system
- Worked on sharing and collaboration features
- Mentored juniors on creating sustainable tech stack based on SOLID principles.
- Implemented storage agnostic information rights management
- Established successful SDLCs for multiple products
- Successfully created POCs for gaining new clients